Nicole Ersing

(419) 345-2159 nicolegiacci@gmail.com Chicago, IL LinkedIn Github Portfolio

Full Stack Developer whose previous teaching experience brings excellent time management and organizational skills to the subject opportunity. I have a strong interest in building creative design elements using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, Javascript, and React, and hope to continue to refine my skill set while bringing intuitive and user-friendly layouts to websites and apps.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University Chicago, Illinois

September 2017 - December 2017

Northwestern Coding Bootcamp Javascript Full Stack Web Development

• Languages learned consisted of HTML/CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose and React js.

Miami University Oxford Ohio

August 2008 - May 2012

Middle Childhood Education with a Bachelors of Science in Education

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Brave Initiatives - Brave Camps Inc.

Operations Intern May 2017 - August 2017

- Tracked expenses and managed accounts using Google drive.
- Assisted campers with basic development concepts in HTML and CSS.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

chews

- Backend Developer
- · A web application that connects travelers with locals, and shows them the hidden gems of their city.
- MERN stack and Auth-0.
- https://chewsapp.herokuapp.com

res.create

- Frontend Developer
- A web application that generates a user's resume based on the data they input and layout they choose.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Materialize, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js.
- https://res-create.herokuapp.com

Pinbox

- Frontend Developer
- A web application that allows users to save their searches in a customizable format.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, APIs, Firebase.
- https://nersing.github.io/Pinbox

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Immaculate Conception St. Joseph School

June 2016 - June 2017

• 6th and 7th grade language arts teacher.

Chicago Public Schools

Horace Greeley Elementary School

June 2014 - June 2016

- 6th and 7th grade language arts teacher.
- Designed and created bilingual/gifted curriculum.

John A Walsh Math and Science Academy

August 2013 - June 2014

8th grade language arts and social studies teacher.